these photos were worth a thousand words
in vensim welcome to watchmojo.com omens
captured in photos for this list we're
looking at some of the most incredible
photos of historic moments we'll be
focusing on stunning shots of pivotal
events and photos that became iconic
representations of their eras number 10
the first man powered heavier-than-air
flight in the 1890s brothers Orville and
Wilbur Wright opened a bicycle shop to
cash in on the latest craze but their
real passion was human flight they began
with gliders before building up to
powered aircraft on December 17th 1903
the brothers made the first manned
flight of a powered aeroplane the Wright
Flyer Orville piloted while Wilbur ran
alongside for balance the moment was
captured in this well-known photo taken
by one John T Daniel's who'd actually
never seen a camera before Orville had
preset the camera but Daniels was so
excited he almost forgot to trigger the
shutter turns out his very first photo
was one of the all-time greats number
nine the attack on Pearl Harbor
until Japan's fateful attack on Pearl
Harbor the US had remained formally
neutral while war raged in Europe the
Japanese plan was to cripple the US
Pacific Fleet
while they invaded US and British
overseas territories on the morning of
December 7th 1941 353 Japanese aircraft
descended on the naval base sinking four
battleships and leaving 2403 americans
dead there is footage of the attack but
there's something truly haunting about
the photos of the event capturing the
awful magnitude of the destruction the
strike provokes the u.s. into joining
the fray marking a major turning point
in the Second World War
number eight raising the flag on Iwo
Jima it's one of the most recognizable
images from World War two together
US Marines heave the American flag up
right atop Mount Suribachi on the island
of Iwo Jima Japan captured by Joe
Rosenthal on February 23rd 1945 the
iconic shot is one in a series taken
around the same time the peak was
captured after four fierce days of
fighting and the flag was actually
second race there as the first was too
small the photo one Rosenthal a Pulitzer
and became an enduring symbol of
Brotherhood victory and determination
the moment is the inspiration for the
Marine Corps War Memorial in George
Washington Memorial Parkway Virginia
number seven the Hindenburg disaster
today it looks like something from
another planet but in 1937 the
Hindenburg was touted as the future of
commercial air travel these hopes were
dashed on May 6 when the German airship
went up in flames during docking at
Lakehurst maxfield Field in New Jersey a
static spark may have ignited the blaze
although the reasons for the fire are
debated the fabric skin and hydrogen
inside went up in flames and the ship
came crashing down killing 36 passengers
and crew this famous photo was taken by
Sam Sher shooting in a hurry from the
hip although an equally memorable photo
of the tragedy was taken by Murray
Becker
the disaster proved to be the last nail
in the coffin for the airship era number
6 VJ Day in Times Square the war was
finally over on August 14 1945 news of
Japan's surrender sent jubilant crowds
cheering through the streets across
America in Times Square thousands
gathered in a rain of cloth scraps and
ticker tape amid the celebration
photojournalist Alfred Eisenstaedt
spotted a US Navy sailor kissing a woman
in what looked like a nurse uniform
later identified as dental assistant
Greta Zimmer Friedman Viktor Jorgensen
shot the same moment from a different
angle
i cinched its photo was an instant
sensation capturing the mood of the
country since the 2010s the narrative
around the photo has changed since
Friedman had not consented to the kiss
however it's remained a cultural icon a
symbol of the war's end number five
migrant mother as the world economy
collapsed drought devastated the
American heartland and dust storms hid
the sky the Great Depression was a dark
time that just seemed to pile one
disaster on top of another in the mid
1930s photojournalist Dorothea Lange
roamed the California countryside
documenting rural
her image of Florence Owens Thompson a
migrant worker of Cherokee descent
summed up the desperation of the times
the lines of worry and the children
huddling beside her capture an anxiety
that was felt across the country Lange's
images resulted in aid being rushed to
the camp of workers but Thompson and her
many children had already moved on
number 4 hiroshima the mushroom cloud of
a nuclear bomb has become a universal
symbol of doom but before August 6 1945
this harrowing new weapon had only been
used in tests at 8:15 a.m. that morning
u.s. bomber Enola Gay released an atomic
bomb nicknamed little boy over the
Japanese city of Hiroshima a
reconnaissance plane carrying scientific
observers took this photo of the
mushroom cloud the city was flattened
leaving a smoking ruin thousands were
vaporized instantly while others died
more slowly from radiation three days
later the u.s. dropped a second bomb on
Nagasaki bringing the total casualties
to between 129 thousand to two hundred
and twenty six thousand Japan
surrendered six days later it was the
world's first introduction to the awful
mite of nuclear weapons number three
tank men even without context tank man
is an immediately arresting image one
man stands alone on a road looking small
as he confronts a line of Tanks On June
4th 1989 the Chinese military fired on
student-led demonstrators in Beijing
killing hundreds and possibly thousands
the schools had been protesting
corruption and calling for democratic
reforms a day after the Tiananmen Square
massacre Associated Press photographer
Jeff Widener caught sight of take man
stepping into the path of the vehicles
bringing them to a standstill before
being dragged away the identity of this
unknown rebel remains a mystery but his
act of defiance led to one of the most
iconic images of the 20th century number
2 the fall of the Berlin Wall
for three decades the Berlin Wall
divided West Berlin from Soviet
controlled East Germany he
was the ultimate symbol of the iron
curtain separating Western Europe and
the Eastern Bloc so it's fall on
November 9th 1989 was about much more
than a concrete barrier that evening an
underprepared East German Communist
official announced that East Germans
would be permitted to cross into the
West it was supposed to be announced the
next day and require visas in response
thousands flocked to the wall
unfortunately the soldiers on guard
decided not to fire but to let them
through as friends and families United
the crowd erupted in wild celebrations
that continued for days their joy
captured in these photos before we
continue be sure to subscribe to our
channel and ring the bell to get
notified about our latest videos you
have the option to be notified for
occasional videos or all of them if
you're on your phone make sure you go
into your settings and switch on
notifications number one man on the moon
on July 20th 1969 rapt viewers sat glued
to their TV screens the footage was
fuzzy but you could still make it out
man's first steps on the moon for the
first time humans had set foot on
another terrestrial body photographs
presented an even clearer picture which
is pretty fortunate because it's a long
way to go for a photo in this shot of
astronaut Buzz Aldrin you can see the
reflection of Apollo 11 commander Neil
Armstrong as he takes the picture and it
wasn't the only iconic shot taken during
the Apollo missions the famous Earthrise
was taken by the crew of Apollo 8 and a
few years later Apollo 17 brought us the
Blue Marble a stunning shot of our home
from a farm do you agree with our picks
check out this other recent clip from
WatchMojo and be sure to subscribe and
ring the bell to be notified about our
latest videos
[Music]