my name is Justin Lauria and today we're
gonna break down the ten easiest tricks
that you can learn when you first start
skateboarding
[Music]
all right so the first trick at the top
of the list is de bunnyhop while you're
riding crouch down and grab the nose and
the tail of the board with your hands
now while holding on jump as high as you
can and pull the board up with you so
that it never leaves your feet you
probably won't be able to get as high as
an ollie but this version is sure to get
you jumping off the ground in this
little time as possible okay so now for
the second trick which is called a
revert for this trick you're going to be
doing a 180 or a half rotation but
you're gonna leave the wheels on the
ground the whole time to accomplish this
first you're gonna rotate your upper
body focusing on bringing your shoulders
around to face forward then using the
momentum from your upper body and gauge
your core and push your back wheels
around until they're riding in front if
you do this properly the wheels should
skid along the concrete and make a
really cool screeching noise the third
trick we're gonna learn is the board
pickup nothing tells the world that you
haven't been skating for very long like
bending down and picking up the board
off of the ground like this instead of
doing it that way pop the tail of the
board down with your foot so that it
jumps off of the ground and then catch
it by the nose while it's still in the
air I personally found that the easiest
way to do this is to start with your
hand position so that your palm is
facing away from your body then catch
the board so that your thumb is on the
bottom part of the deck a variation of
this move would be to kick the board up
and then try to get the board to balance
on top of your foot for a moment as you
bring the board up in to your hand
the fourth trick on the list is called
the caveman to do the easiest version of
a caveman you're gonna start with the
board in your leading hand with your
thumb on the grip tape swing the board
away from you and then as it starts to
swing back toward you jump as high as
you can off of the ground and try to
land on the board with one foot over top
of each set of wheels now there are a
bunch of really fun variations
so be sure to check out my trick tip on
caveman's
which I'll put a link to right at the
end of the video the fifth trick is
another stylish and very useful way of
getting back on your board and I call it
the throw down you can use this maneuver
as a way to get up to speed on your
board in a hurry or when you have a
really short run up just like for the
caveman you're gonna start by holding
the board in your leading hand with your
thumb on top of the grip tape facing the
way you want to start riding and with
the board at your side start to take a
few steps forward as you drag the tail
on the ground beside you when you're
ready to hop on let go of the board with
your leading hand and jump off of the
foot you normally ride with in bag and
place your front foot on the board
directly over the front set of wheels
follow that up by placing your back foot
on the tail and now you're instantly up
to full speed and you didn't even have
to push one time if you want to get a
little fancier with this one you can
start with the board upside down like
this and when you drop it tip it a
little bit to one side as you jump on
top of it causing it to flip over
perfectly for you to land on top of the
grip tape now the sixth trick on the
list is what you might think of as a
wheelie if you've ever ridden a bicycle
but on a skateboard this trick is called
a manual to do a manual you're gonna
lift your front wheels into the air by
bending your front knee rather than just
leaning your whole body backwards as you
do this try to find the balance point
and hold yourself in that position with
the front wheels off of the ground for
as long as possible this one takes a bit
of practice to hold for more than a few
seconds but if you keep at it you'll
eventually be able to hold a manual for
as long as you want trick number seven
is called the hippy jump which
essentially just involves jumping off of
the board while
stays on the ground to perform this
trick you're going to start with your
feet positioned a little more towards
the center of the board making sure that
neither of them is on the nose or on the
tail when you first start trying you can
practice just jumping off the board
without rolling to help you get a feel
for the maneuver once you progress to
try net while moving take care not to
lean toward the nose order of the tail
too much as you jump off the board and
as you land back on it because if you do
the board can shoot out from underneath
you and you can end up taking the slam
after you master the rolling hip you
jump you can try landing some of these
variations okay so let's move on the
trick number eight which I call the
standing rail flip for this trick you're
going to start with the board resting on
the ground on its side while you're
standing on the ground next to it with
your toes pointed at the griptape using
your usual back foot kick the edge of
the tail of the board down while pulling
your foot back slightly to cause the
board to start flipping as you do this
simultaneously jump off of your leaving
foot and try to land on top of the board
after it is completed whatever amount of
flips feels most comfortable for you I
found that allowing the board to flip
almost two times while rotating 180
degrees has been the most consistent
motion for me all right so the ninth
trick on the list is the nose stall this
trick is as easy as positioning your
front foot over top of the nose of your
board riding on to a curb or a short
ledge and then lifting up your back foot
so that the back wheels come off the
ground from this position you can push
off of the curb and ride away in fakie
stance or hold the board up into your
hand with your
put into a fakie caveman okay so now the
tenth and final trick on our list is
called the wraparound for this trick
you're going to start with the board
resting on the ground on its side again
but this time you're going to stand
facing away from the board with the heel
of your back foot position directly in
front of the back wheels simultaneously
kick your foot back in the circular
motion to cause the board to wrap around
your back foot and jump off of your
front foot to try to land on the board
as it lands on its wheels and find you
with one foot over each set of wheels
for a much more thorough breakdown of
how to perform this trick again you can
click the link that I'll put it right at
the end of the video alright guys so I
hope this video gave you some ideas for
some tricks you can work on when you're
just getting started and also showed you
that there's really no good reason to
have to start with the ollie is your
first trick once you get some of these
moves down you'll have a lot more
control over your board and it'll make
them into ollie that much easier if you
enjoyed this video make sure to
subscribe so you can stay up to date
with weekly skateboarding tutorials and
as usual never stop improving
[Music]